<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-21T22:16:21+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">nicolobertani.github.io</title><subtitle>Personal website of Nicol&amp;ograve Bertani, with latest news, research, and blogposts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ambiguity and Accountability in Environmental Choices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/01/TripleAmbiguity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ambiguity and Accountability in Environmental Choices" /><published>2020-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/01/TripleAmbiguity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/01/TripleAmbiguity.html">&lt;p&gt;In an experimental setting with real incentives, we elicit the attitude towards attribute risk and ambiguity when outcomes are environmental consequences. We explore the effect of accountability on these attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In an experimental setting with real incentives, we elicit the attitude towards attribute risk and ambiguity when outcomes are environmental consequences. We explore the effect of accountability on these attitudes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Urban Planning of Safer Cities based on Hierarchical Spatio-Temporal Forecasting of Crime</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/01/PhillyCrime.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Urban Planning of Safer Cities based on Hierarchical Spatio-Temporal Forecasting of Crime" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/01/PhillyCrime</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/01/PhillyCrime.html">&lt;p&gt;We explore the effect of granular features of the urban geography, such as schools, stores or churches, on the spatio-temporal dynamics of urban crime.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We explore the effect of granular features of the urban geography, such as schools, stores or churches, on the spatio-temporal dynamics of urban crime.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Joint Bottom-Up Method for Hierarchical Time-Series: Application to Australian Tourism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/16/JBU.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joint Bottom-Up Method for Hierarchical Time-Series: Application to Australian Tourism" /><published>2020-01-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-01-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/16/JBU</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/16/JBU.html">&lt;p&gt;Many applications involve a hierarchy of time-series, where values at the bottom level aggregate to values at higher levels. Forecasts of such hierarchical data need to be accurate, probabilistic, and coherent in the sense of respecting hierarchical aggregation. While recent developments have explicitly modeled every time-series in the hierarchy, we show, under general conditions, that hierarchical data can be modeled jointly by considering only its bottom-level series and their contemporaneous covariance. Inspired by this result, we devise a Bayesian method that models bottom-level series jointly, takes into account their contemporaneous covariance, and performs automatic selection of lag terms, both within and across series. The model copes with high-dimensional data, and outputs both point and probabilistic forecasts. Additionally, it returns posterior distributions of all parameters, which can be used for inference. As a case study, we apply our method to make recommendations on planning and promotion of domestic tourism in Australia. Our model reveals the hidden spatio-temporal dynamics of different types of domestic tourism in Australia, and allows us to explore how promotional investments could be localized to develop tourism in accordance with the declared desiderata of the Australian government.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Many applications involve a hierarchy of time-series, where values at the bottom level aggregate to values at higher levels. Forecasts of such hierarchical data need to be accurate, probabilistic, and coherent in the sense of respecting hierarchical aggregation. While recent developments have explicitly modeled every time-series in the hierarchy, we show, under general conditions, that hierarchical data can be modeled jointly by considering only its bottom-level series and their contemporaneous covariance. Inspired by this result, we devise a Bayesian method that models bottom-level series jointly, takes into account their contemporaneous covariance, and performs automatic selection of lag terms, both within and across series. The model copes with high-dimensional data, and outputs both point and probabilistic forecasts. Additionally, it returns posterior distributions of all parameters, which can be used for inference. As a case study, we apply our method to make recommendations on planning and promotion of domestic tourism in Australia. Our model reveals the hidden spatio-temporal dynamics of different types of domestic tourism in Australia, and allows us to explore how promotional investments could be localized to develop tourism in accordance with the declared desiderata of the Australian government.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fast and Simple Adaptive Elicitations: Experimental Test for Probability Weighting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/01/Elicit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fast and Simple Adaptive Elicitations: Experimental Test for Probability Weighting" /><published>2019-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/01/Elicit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/01/Elicit.html">&lt;p&gt;We propose a new adaptive procedure for the measurement of decision models. Our procedure bounds the function of the decision model, sequentially halves the maximal distance between its bounds, and incrementally restricts the feasible space of associated parameters. It relies on approximating splines that improve tractability and descriptiveness, enriching results. It grants concise unsupervised experiments: ten choices on average suffice.
We apply and validate our procedure in an experimental elicitation of the probability weighting function. Our procedure faithfully captures empirical regularities in probability weighting. In addition, it reveals systematic distortions introduced by standard parametric forms, and sheds new light on the pervasiveness of possibility and certainty effects in close proximity to the probability boundaries (i.e. p=0 and p=1).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We propose a new adaptive procedure for the measurement of decision models. Our procedure bounds the function of the decision model, sequentially halves the maximal distance between its bounds, and incrementally restricts the feasible space of associated parameters. It relies on approximating splines that improve tractability and descriptiveness, enriching results. It grants concise unsupervised experiments: ten choices on average suffice. We apply and validate our procedure in an experimental elicitation of the probability weighting function. Our procedure faithfully captures empirical regularities in probability weighting. In addition, it reveals systematic distortions introduced by standard parametric forms, and sheds new light on the pervasiveness of possibility and certainty effects in close proximity to the probability boundaries (i.e. p=0 and p=1).</summary></entry></feed>